Guide to the Lady St. Helier Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Lady St. Helier papers
1847-1955
GEN MSS 477
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.73
(7 boxes)
Letters received by Lady St. Helier and other members of her family, particularly her daughter, Dorothy Stewart Allhusen. The letters, from many notable authors, political figures, clergymen, and members of English and Scottish aristocratic families, mainly concern social engagements and personal news; several letters to Lord Jeune (later Baron St. Helier) concern political matters and legal cases. Correspondents include Sir Austen Chamberlain, Pearl May Teresa Richards Craigie, Kate Greenaway, Edith Wharton, and Sir Evelyn Wood.
Jeune, Susan Mary Elizabeth Stewart-Mackenzie, Lady, 1931-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Lady St. Helier Papers were a gift in memory of Dorothy Allhusen from Richard L. Purdy, Yale 1925, in 1965.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Lady St. Helier Papers consist primarily of social and personal letters received by Susan Mary Elizabeth Stewart-Mackenzie, Lady St. Helier, and one of her daughters, Dorothy Stewart Allhusen. There are also some letters to Francis Henry Jeune, Baron St. Helier; Lady St. Helier's other daughter, Marjorie Fremantle Brodrick, Lady Midleton, and her husband, William St. John Fremantle Brodrick, the Earl of Midleton; and a few other recipients.
The collection has been organized into one series, Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by author, and spans the years 1847-1955, with the bulk of the material dating from between 1885 and 1915.
While in most cases the number of letters under a given correspondent is ten or fewer, there are more substantial groups of letters from several individuals, including Sir Austen Chamberlain (27), Pearl May Teresa Richards Craigie (62), Kate Greenaway (126), Sir Henry Thompson (110), Bishop James Edward Welldon (49), Edith Wharton (38), and Sir Evelyn Wood (82). The correspondence is mainly social in nature and concerns invitations, parties, country houses, and entertainments. Some letters to Baron St. Helier concern politics and legal cases, including those by Viscount Alverstone, William Gladstone, and the Earl of Balfour.
Friendship -- Great Britain; Upper class women; Upper class -- Great Britain; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 20th Century; Women -- Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 20th Century; Allhusen, Dorothy; Austin, Alfred, 1835-1913; Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), 1860-1937; Chamberlain, Austen, Sir, 1863-1937; Chamberlain, Joseph, 1836-1914; Dufferin and Ava, Frederick Temple Hamilton-Temple-Blackwood, Marquess of, 1875-1930; Gladstone, W. E. (William Ewart), 1809-1898; Göschen, G. J. (Georg Joachim), 1752-1828; Greenaway, Kate, 1846-1901; Hobbes, John Oliver, 1867-1906; Hope, Anthony, 1863-1933; Iddesleigh, Stafford Henry Northcote, Earl of, 1818-1887; Jeune, Francis Henry, Sir, 1843-1905; Jeune, Susan Mary Elizabeth Stewart-Mackenzie, Lady, 1931-; Midleton, William St. John Fremantle Brodrick, Earl of, 1856-; Thompson, Henry, Sir, 1820-1904; Thurston, E. Temple (Ernest Temple), 1879-1933; Welldon, J. E. C. (James Edward Cowell), 1854-1937; Wood, Evelyn, 1838-1919
- Correspondence
  - ACTON, JOHN EMERICH EDWARD DAHLBERG ACTON, BARON
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ADDERLEY, J. G. (JAMES GRANVILLE)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AIDÉ, HAMILTON
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ALEXANDRA, QUEEN CONSORT OF EDWARD VII
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1911 Jul 11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ALVERSTONE, RICHARD EVERARD WEBSTER, VISCOUNT
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1888 Feb 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ANDERSON, PERCY
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1918 Aug 26 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ARNIM, ELIZABETH VON
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Countess Mary Annette Beauchamp Russell, Box 5, folder 327
  - ARNOLD-FOSTER, H.O. (HUGH OAKELEY)
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1903 Oct 11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ASHBURNE, EDWARD GIBSON
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1889 Mar 13 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ATHERTON, GERTRUDE FRANKLIN HORn
    - 3 ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - AUSTIN, ALFRED, SIR
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1895 Jun 5 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1896 Jul 22 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - ALS to "Madeleine and Dorothy", 1891 Mar 10 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 3 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - AMS, "To Dorothy Stanley, on the Eve of her Marriage": sonnet, 1896 Jul (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - AVEBURY, JOHN LUBBOCK
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1904 Dec 29 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - BAGOT, RICHARD
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1917 Jun 28 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - BALFOUR, ARTHUR JAMES BALFOUR, EARL OF
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1902 Jul 15 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - ALS to "My dear Sr. John", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - BANCROFT, MARIE EFFIE, LADY
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, [1896] May 21 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - BARRIE, J. M. (JAMES MATTHEW), SIR
    - 6 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1913, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 5 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1894, 1915, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - BAYARD, THOMAS FRANCIS
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1894 Sep 9 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - BEERBOHM, MAX, SIR
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1911 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - BENNETT, ARNOLD
    - TLS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1916 Feb 5 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - BENSON, EDWARD FREDERIC
    - 5 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1900-01, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 2 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - BENSON, EDWARD WHITE, ABP. OF CANTERBURY
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1891 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1888 Nov 26 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - BENSON, ROBERT HUGH
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - BERESFORD, CHARLES WILLIAM DE LA POER
    - 8 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1895-1910, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1897 Jan 30 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - ALS to "Madeleine", 1895 Jan 31 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - BERNARD, JOHN HENRY, ABP. OF DUBLIN
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1919 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - BERRY, MARY
    - ALS to Mr. Mackenzie, 1847 Apr 28 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - BIRKENHEAD, FREDERICK EDWIN SMITH, EARL OF
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1906 Apr 26 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - BLACKWOOD, ALGERNON
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1914 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - BLAINE, JAMES GILLESPIE
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.y. May 22 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - BLUMENTHAL, JACQUES
    - ALS, to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - BOULANGER, GEORGES ERNEST JEAN MARIE
    - ALS to [Lady St. Helier], 1889 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - BOWEN, CHARLES SYNGE CHRISTOPHER BOWEN, BARON
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, [1881?] Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - BRADFORD, EDWARD RIDLEY COLBORNE, SIR
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1897 Aug 13 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - BRADLEY, GEORGE GRANVILLE
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1890 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1893 Jun 5 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - ALS to Lord Selbourne, 1894 Jun 18 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - BRAITHWAITE, LILIAN, DAME
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.y. May 4 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - BRIGHT, JOHN
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1887 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - BROADHURST, HENRY
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1887 Jan 26 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - BROUGHAM, HENRY PETER, BARON
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1860 Jun 30 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - BROUGHTON, JOHN CAM HOBHOUSE, BARON
    - ALS to Mrs. Mackenzie, 1854 Dec 21 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - BROUGHTON, RHODA
    - 2 ALS to Lady St. Helier (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - BRYCE, JAMES, VISCOUNT
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, [1905] Apr 27 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - BULLER, CHARLES
    - ALS to "My Dear Stanley", 1848 Feb 13 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - BULLER, REDVERS HENRY, SIR
    - 3 ALS to "My dear Brodrick", 1892, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - BURDETT-COUTTS, ANGELA GEORGINA, BARONESS
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1896 Feb 9 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - BURNAND, FRANCIS COWLEY, SIR
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - BURNETT, FRANCES HODGSON
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - BUTLER, AGNATA FRANCES RAMSAY
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.y. Apr 18 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - BUTLER, HENRY MONTAGU
    - 2 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1905, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - 2 ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1886, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - ALS to Lord Midleton, 1914 Mar 11 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - CAMBON, PAUL
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1915 Feb 11 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - CARNARVON, HENRY HOWARD MOLYNEUX, EARL OF
    - 5 ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1886-89 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - CARNOCK, ARTHUR NICOLSON, BARON
    - TLS in the third person to Austin Lee, concerning Dorothy Allhusen, 1915 Feb 16 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - CARSON, EDWARD HENRY, BARON
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - 8 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1900-09, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - CHAMBERLAIN, AUSTEN, SIR
    - 8 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1898-1919 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - 17 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1897-1906, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - 2 ALS to Mrs. Brodrick, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - CHAMBERLAIN, JOSEPH
    - 10 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1885-1909 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - 6 ALS to St. John Brodrick, 1897-1901 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - CHAMBERS, ELSIE
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - CHAPLIN, ----
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1910 Oct 27 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - CHURCHILL, CLEMENTINE OGILVIE, LADY
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1954 Aug 9 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - CHURCHILL, ODETTE MARIE CELINE
    - ALS and TLS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - CLIFFORD, LUCY JANE
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - 7 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1904-1911, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - COLERIDGE, JOHN DUKE COLERIDGE, BARON
    - 5 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1884-91, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - 2 ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1883-88 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - COLLIER, PRICE
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1913 Jul 5 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - COLLINGS, JESSE
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - COLVIN, SIDNEY, SIR
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1903 Aug 23 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - COOPER, EDWARD HERBERT
    - 2 ALS and 2 TLS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1908, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - CORELLI, MARIE
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1896 Apr 12 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - COWANS, JOHN STEVEN, SIR
    - TLS to Lady St. Helier, 1917 May 23 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - COWIE, LAURA
    - To "M. Solano", [1910?] (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - CRAIGIE, PEARL MARY TERESA RICHARDS
    - 3 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1899, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1899 Mar 10 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - 57 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1898-1905, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 92-93)
    - ALS to Madeleine, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - CRAIK, HENRY, SIR
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1912 Jul 21 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - CRANBROOK, GATHORNE GATHORNE-HARDY, EARL OF
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1891 Feb 18 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - CREIGHTON, M. (MANDELL), BP. OF LONDON
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1896 Nov 11 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - CREWE, ROBERT OFFLEY ASHBURTON CREWE-MILNES, MARQUIS OF
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1915 Aug 26 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - CRICHTON-BROWNE, JAMES, SIR
    - ALS to "Mr. Jones", 1894 Mar 13 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - CROMER, EVELYN BARING, EARL OF
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - ALS to "My dear Brodrick", 1900 Sep 2 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - CROSS, RICHARD ASSHETON, VISCOUNT
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - CURZON, GEORGE NATHANIEL CURZON, MARQUIS OF
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - DASENT, GEORGE WEBBE, SIR
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1891, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - DAVIDSON, RANDALL THOMAS, ABP. OF CANTERBURY
    - TLS to Lady St. Helier, 1914 Jun 18 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - 2 ALS to Lady Midleton, 1909, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - DAVIS, RICHARD HARDING
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - DAVITT, MICHAEL
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - DAWKINS, CLINTON EDWARD, SIR
    - ALS to Lady Midleton, 1903 Oct 6 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - DELYSIA, ALICE
    - TLS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1916 Jul 14 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - DEPEW, CHAUNCEY MITCHELL
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1894 Jul 28 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - DERBY, FREDERICK ARTHUR STANLEY, EARL OF
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - DEVONSHIRE, SPENCER COMPTON CAVENDISH, DUKE OF
    - 2 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1888, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - DICKSEE, FRANCIS BERNARD
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - DILKE, CHARLES WENTWORTH, SIR
    - 2 ALS to Baron St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - DILLON, JOHN
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - DOYLE, ARTHUR CONAN, SIR
    - 6 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1897-1900, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - DU CHAILLU, PAUL B. (PAUL BELLONI)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1895 Aug 9 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - DUFFERIN AND AVA, FREDERICK TEMPLE BLACKWOOD, MARQUIS OF
    - ALS and TLS to Lady St. Helier, 1901, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1895 Nov 18 (Box 2, Folder 120)
      Scope and Contents
      Accompanied by typescript copy of letter to his son, Basil
    - ALS and 8 TLS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - ALS to Madeleine, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - ALS to Lady Midleton, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - DUMAURIER, GERALD, SIR
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - DUNDONALD, DOUGLAS MACKINNON HAMILTON COCHRANE, EARL OF
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1889 Sep 26 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - ELCHO, HUGH FRANCIS WEMYSS, LORD
    - AL fragment to unidentified, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - ELY, JANE HOPE-VERE LOFTUS, MARCHIONESS OF
    - ALS to "My dearest Julia", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - FAWCETT, MILLICENT GARRETT, DAME
    - 3 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1894, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - FINLAY, ROBERT BANNATYNE FINLAY, VISCOUNT
    - 2 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1916, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - FORBES-ROBERTSON, JOHNSTON, SIR
    - 2 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1905, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - FORD, HENRY JUSTICE
    - AL fragment to unidentified, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - FORSTER, W. E. (WILLIAM EDWARD)
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1885 Mar 24 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - FORTESCUE, JOHN WILLIAM, SIR
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1911 Jun 18 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - FOSTER, MICHAEL, SIR
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1900 Feb 10 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - FRASER, DONALD
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier ("Mrs. Stanley", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - FREDERICK, CHRISTIAN CHARLES AUGUSTUS, PRINCE
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1891 Mar 29 (Box 2, Folder 137)
    - 2 ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1885, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - FRENCH, JOHN DENTON PINKSTONE
    See: John Denton Pinkstone French, Earl of Ypres, Box 6, folders 433-435
  - FRIEDLAENDER, THEKLA
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier ("Mrs. Stanley"), 1881 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - FROUDE, JAMES ANTHONY
    - 2 ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - FURNISS, HARRY
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1899 Dec 29 (Box 2, Folder 141)
      Illustrated in pen and ink.
  - GARSTIN, WILLIAM EDMUND, SIR
    - 4 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1912, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - GEORGE, SECOND DUKE OF CAMBRIDGE
    - 7 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1894-1900 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - GEORGE V, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN
    - DS conferring the Order of St. Leopold on Lord Midleton, 1922 May 18 (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - GILL, CHARLES FREDERICK, SIR
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1914 Aug 26 (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - GLADSTONE, WILLIAM EWART
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1892 Dec 19 (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - GLYN, EDWARD CARR, BP. OF PETERBOROUGH
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - GLYN, ELINOR
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - GOLDSCHMIDT, OTTO
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1888 Feb 24 (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - GORDON, JANET
    See: Cecil Blanche Fitzgerald Woodham-Smith, Box 6, folder 429
  - GOSCHEN, G. J. (GEORGE JOACHIM), VISCOUNT
    - 8 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1896-1900, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - 2 ALS to Baron St. Helier, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - 5 ALS to Dorothy Stamley Allhusen, 1897-1900, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - 2 ALS to "Madeleine and Dorothy", 1890, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - 4 ALS to "Madeleine", 1903, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - GOSSE, WILLIAM, SIR
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1904 Jan 25 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - 2 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1904, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - GOULD, FRANCIS CARRUTHERS, SIR
    - AL in the third person to Lady St. Helier, 1904 Feb 20 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - GREENAWAY, KATE
    - 6 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1894-98 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - 113 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1894-1901 (Box 3, Folder 159-166)
      2 with illustrations.
    - 7 ALS to Madeleine Stanley, 1898-99 (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - GREGORY, ISABELLA AUGUSTA, LADY
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.y. Jun 29 (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - GREGORY, WILLIAM HENRY, SIR
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.y. Dec 27 (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - GRENFELL, FRANCIS WALLACE, BARON
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.y. Jul 8 (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - GREY, ALBERT HENRY GEORGE GREY, EARL
    - ALS to Madeleine Stanley, 1898 Aug 29 (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - GREY OF FALLODON, EDWARD GREY, VISCOUNT
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1902 Jan 26 (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - GRIMTHORPE, EDMUND BECKETT, BARON
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1886 Feb 6 (Box 3, Folder 173)
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1891 May 17 (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - GUTHRIE, THOMAS ANSTEY
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1898 Jan 12 (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - HALDANE, R. B. (RICHARD BURDON HALDANE), VISCOUNT
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, [1903?] Apr 23 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1900 Jan 26 (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - HALSBURY, HARDINGE STANLEY GIFFARD, EARL OF
    - 4 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1888, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - 3 ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1894-1905 (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - 2 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1894, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 180)
  - HAMILTON, CICELY MARY
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1917 Apr 27 (Box 3, Folder 181)
  - HAMILTON, GEORGE FRANCIS, LORD
    - 2 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1898, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 182)
  - HAMILTON, IAN, SIR
    - 2 ALS to Lady Midleton, 1903, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 183)
  - HANNEN, JAMES HANNEN, BARON
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1891 Feb 16 (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1891 Jan 22 (Box 3, Folder 185)
  - HARCOURT, WILLIAM GEORGE GRANVILLE VERNON, SIR
    - 5 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1900-04 (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1893 Dec 12 (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1901 Jul 15 (Box 3, Folder 188)
  - HATZFELDT, PAUL, GRAF VON
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1885 Dec 4 (Box 3, Folder 189)
      In French.
  - HAUSSMANN, GEORGES EUGENE, BARON
    - ALS to the Countess of Tweeddale, 1879 Sep 15 (Box 3, Folder 190)
  - HAWKINS, ANTHONY HOPE, SIR
    - 12 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1897-1900 (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - 11 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1899-1924 (Box 3, Folder 192)
    - 13 ALS to Madeleine Stanley, 1899-1902, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 193)
  - HAY, JOHN
    - 6 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1889-1904 (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - AMS poem on Mrs. Austen Lee, 1894 Sep 19 (Box 3, Folder 195)
  - HELENA AUGUSTA VICTORIA, PRINCESS
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 196)
    - 5 ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1881-93 (Box 3, Folder 197)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1900 Jan 8 (Box 3, Folder 198)
    - 4 ALS to "Dearest Mary", 1887-1914, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 199)
  - HENSCHEL, GEORGE, SIR
    - 3 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1879-85, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1914 Jan 13 (Box 4, Folder 201)
  - HERKOMER, HUBERT VON, SIR
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1892 Aug 19 (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - HERSCHELL, FARRER HERSCHELL, BARON
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1886 Feb 27 (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - HICHENS, ROBERT SMYTHE
    - AL in the third person to Lady St. Helier, [1913?] Jun 7 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1913 Jun 1 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - ALS to "Madam", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 206)
  - HICKS BEACH, MICHAEL EDWARD, SIR
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1896 Dec 17 (Box 4, Folder 207)
  - HOBBS, JOHN OLIVER
    See: Pearl Mary Teresa Richards Craigie, Box 2, folders 90-94
  - HOLLIS, CHRISTOPHER
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - HOPE, ANTHONY
    See: Sir Anthony Hope Hawkins, Box 3, folders 191-193
  - HOUGHTON, STANLEY
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1913 May 12 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - HUNT, THORNTON
    - ALS to Lord Stanley of Alderley, 1861 Feb 7 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - HUNT, VIOLET
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.y. Sep 16 (Box 4, Folder 211)
  - HUXLEY, THOMAS HENRY
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1889 Apr 22 (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1894 Oct 10 (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - HYNDMAN, HENRY MAYERS
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1886 Mar 1 (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - HYTHE, BETTINA VON
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 215)
  - IDDESLEIGH, STAFFORD HENRY NORTHCOTE, EARL OF
    - 13 ALS and 2 AL fragments to Lady St. Helier, 1876-80, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 216)
  - IRVING, HENRY, SIR
    - 2 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1889, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 217)
  - IRVING, H. B. (HENRY BRODRIBB)
    - 2 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1910, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 218)
  - JACOMB-HOOD, G. P. (GEORGE PERCY)
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1912 Jul 2 (Box 4, Folder 219)
  - JAMES, HENRY
    - 3 ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 220)
  - JONES, HENRY ARTHUR
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1897 Oct 1 (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - 8 ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1900-21, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 222)
  - JONES, WILLIAM BASIL TICHELL, BP. OF ST. DAVIDS
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1886 Nov 1 (Box 4, Folder 223)
  - KILLANAN, MICHAEL MORRIS, BARON
    See: Baron Michael Morris, Box 4, folder 286
  - KITCHENER, HORATIO HERBERT KITCHENER, EARL OF
    - AL to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 224)
  - KNOBLOCK, EDWARD
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - LABOUCHERE, HENRY DU PRE
    - 2 ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 226)
  - LANG, COSMO GORDON, ABP. OF CANTERBURY
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, 1908 May 29 (Box 4, Folder 227)
      Signed "Stepney."
  - LANSDOWNE, HENRY CHARLES KEITH, MARQUESS OF
    - 3 ALS to Lady St. Helier, 1895-98, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 228)
  - LANSDOWNE, HENRY PETTY-FITZMAURICE, MARQUESS OF
    - ALS to "My Dear Stanley", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - LAVERY, JOHN, SIR
    - ALS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1914 Dec 21 (Box 4, Folder 230)
  - LAW, ANDREW BONAR
    - TLS to Lady St. Helier, 1916 May 15 (Box 4, Folder 231)
    - 6 ALS and 1 TLS to Dorothy Stanley Allhusen, 1911-15, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 232)
  - LECKY, WILLIAM EDWARD HARTPOLE
    - ALS to Baron St. Helier, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 233)
  - LEE, VERNON
    See: Violet Paget, Box 5, folder 297
  - LEIGHTON OF STRETTON, FREDERIC LEIGHTON, BARON
    - ALS to Lady St. Helier, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 234)